Michael Nchor

summary

A Developer with a degree in Mathematics and Computer Science. I am 4+ years into my development journey. I'm a quick learner and collaborate closely with clients to create efficient, and user-friendly solutions that solve real-world problems.

Skills

C#.NET, ReactJS, Javascript, NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, SQL(Server), P5.JS, Tailwind, Bootstrap, Wordpress, HTML, CSS, Python, R, MATLAB, C, Bash, Latex, Git, Github, Azure DevOps, Web Development, Data Analysis, Parallel Computing, Ubuntu, E-R Modelling in IDERA ER studio.

Experience ___

University Information Technology Services (UITS)

Kumasi, Ghana

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER (NATIONAL SERVICE)

Oct. 2022 - PRESENT

- Developed Web Applications in **C# using the .NET** framework.
- A Student File Management System to help manage student's prospective application information and documents.
- Collaborated with a colleague to develop a Student Card Management System to help Students of KNUST identify themselves with digital ID cards which can be scanned to verify student status.
- Testing and Data Entry for a timetable application to help departments in KNUST schedule classes and meetings efficiently.
- Development of a Shopping Cart Application.
- Research on ESP's Journals and Cloud Computing.

International Learning Planners(ILP Overseas)

India

DIGITAL MARKETING (INTERNSHIP)

Nov. 2021 - Apr. 2022

- Won Best Performer Premium Certificate for Dec. 2021 and Jan. 2022
- Promoted from intern to Team Leader Officer, Team Leader Manager and Head of Department for Digital Marketing Domain
- Produced Blogs, SEO and Engaging Content (Videos and Posters) for ILP Overseas website and Social Media Platforms that boosted publicity. The tools and applications used were **Canva, Photoshop, Screaming Frog**

Freelance

WEB AND SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT FREELANCING

Part-time

• Build websites and Applications for clients and teach how to code.

Projects ___

Superstore Application

Feb. 2023 - Apr. 2023

 A Complete Online store Application with Authentication and Authorization, Admin and User routes, Paypal Payment, Currency change, product review and more. Built with ExpressJS, NodeJS, MongoDB, EJS Templating, HTML, CSS and Javascript.

Student File System

June. 2023 - July. 2023

An Application to help manage student's prospective application information and documents. Features include user
Authentication as Admin or Student, Create, Edit, Delete, View, Applicant Advanced Search and Document Upload
developed with C# using the .NET framework

Sketching Application

Sept. 2020 - March. 2021

A Complete Drawing Application like Microsoft Paint for creative drawing shapes, applying color, editing, image upload, stamps, etc. Developed with P5.jS libraries, HTML, CSS and JS

Slack Clone Messaging Application

Apr. 2023 - May. 2023

A Complete Slack clone with Authentication and Authorization, Channel creation, direct messaging, texting
with images, videos and emojis, sharing and watching external links in app (e.g. Youtube) and more. Developed with ReactJS, ExpressJS, NodeJS and Stream API.

Endless Runner Video Game

Sept. 2019 - March. 2020

• An adventure game, "adventure boy", where player has to escape obstacles, risk losing lives to earn coins and capture the flag at the end. Built with **P5.JS libraries, HTML, CSS and JS**

Synomemes Web Application

Jan. 2022 - Jul. 2022

Worked with colleage as Frontend Developer on synomemes social media application for sharing memes. With Authentication and Authorization, Meme sharing, likes, comments, and more. Built with PHP, Laravel, MySQL, HTML, CSS and Javascript.

Other Projects

Jan. 2019 - Jul. 2023

• Social Media Meme App (Synomemes), Google keep clone, Sketching Application, Endless Runner App, Hall of Music Website, Warehouse Management Application, Todolist Application, Themepark Website, Data and Music Visualizer Applications, Rock-paper-scissors application and so on.

Education _

Goldsmiths University of London

UK

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Sept. 2019 to Present

• Web Development, Introduction to Programming I, II, Object-Oriented Programming, Algorithms and Data Structures, Google It Professional

Kwame Nkrumah University of Science and Technology

Kumasi, Ghana

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN MATHEMATICS, CWA 77.11 (FIRST CLASS HONS)

Sept. 2018 to Nov. 2022

• Scientific Computing, Numerical Analysis, Mathematical Programming

ALX Software Engineering Programme

Ghana

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING CERTIFICATE

Jan. 2023 to Present

• Restful APIs, ES6, ReactJS, Redux

Certificates

Google IT Professional Certificate

COURSERA.COM Aug. 2020 - Oct. 2020

• IT Security, Techinical Support Fundamentals, Operating Systems, Computer Networking and System Administration and IT Infrastructure Certificates

Responsive Web Design Certificate

FREECODECAMP.COM Sept. 2021 - Oct. 2021

Completed self paced program on Freecodecamp.com

Achievements ____

Organising Secretary of the Association of Mathematics

KNUST Jan. 2021 - Sept. 2022

• Voted the Organising Secretary of the Association of Mathematics, KNUST.

Winner of Contest 1 of an Inter-departmental Quiz

KNUST Jul. 2021 - Jul. 2021

• Co-contestant for Department of Mathematics and Winner of Contest 1, Prof. Amekuzi Inter-departmental Quiz 2021 between 11 departments College of Science, KNUST.

Best Performer of the Month Premium Certificates

ILP OverseasDec. 2021 - Jan. 2022

• Best performing intern during my time at ILP Overseas.

Languages

Professional Proficiency English, Akan